The French Dispatch of the Liberty, Kansas Evening Sun is a
drama, comedy film directed by Wes Anderson.
The staff of an American magazine based in France puts out its last issue, with stories featuring an
artist sentenced to life imprisonment, student riots, and a kidnapping resolved by a chef.
Moses Rosenthaler, played by Benicio del Toro.
Julian Cadazio, played by Adrien Brody.
J.K.L. Berensen, played by Tilda Swinton.
Simone, played by Léa Seydoux.
Lucinda Krementz, played by Frances McDormand.
Zeffirelli, played by Timothée Chalamet.
The French Dispatch of the Liberty, Kansas Evening Sun (or simply The French Dispatch) is a 2021 American anthology comedy drama film written,
directed, and co-produced by Wes Anderson from a story he conceived with Roman Coppola, Hugo Guinness, and Jason Schwartzman.
It features an expansive ensemble cast and follows three different storylines as the French news
bureau of the fictional Liberty, Kansas Evening Sun newspaper publishes its final issue.
The first segment, "The Concrete Masterpiece", follows an incarcerated and unstable
painter, and stars Benicio del Toro, Adrien Brody, Tilda Swinton and Léa Seydoux.
The second, "Revisions to a Manifesto", is inspired by the May 68 student protests,
and stars Frances McDormand, Timothée Chalamet, and Lyna Khoudri.
The third, "The Private Dining Room of the Police Commissioner",  follows the kidnapping of a
police commissioner's son and stars Jeffrey Wright, Mathieu Amalric, and Stephen Park.
Bill Murray also stars as Arthur Howitzer Jr., the paper's editor, while Owen Wilson appears in a
short segment that introduces the film's fictional setting of Ennui-sur-Blasé.
The project was first mentioned in August 2018 as an
untitled musical set after World War II.
That December, the film was officially announced, with
Anderson calling it a "love letter to journalists".
Filming took place between November 2018 and March
2019, with cinematographer Robert D.
Yeoman, in the city of Angoulême, France.
In post-production, editing was completed by Andrew Weisblum
and the score was composed by Alexandre Desplat.
Following a delay from 2020, The French Dispatch premiered at the Cannes Film Festival on July 12, 2021, and
was theatrically released in the United States by Searchlight Pictures on October 22, 2021.
It received generally positive reviews, with praise for its
score, production design, and performances.
It has grossed $46 million worldwide against its budget of $25 million.
The film explores themes of art collector,
journalist, small town, france, poison.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.